<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>two-loop on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/tags/two-loop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in two-loop on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/tags/two-loop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publication: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, the open access version of our paper Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC was published online in Physics Letters B today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, our paper Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprint: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</guid>
      <description>In our preprint appearing on arXiv today, Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC, we use the two-loop amplitudes from Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders along with the real corrections to obtain differential cross sections of gluon-initiated diphoton-plus-jet production at NLO.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
