<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phys. Let. B: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, the open access version of our paper Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC was published online in Physics Letters B today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, our paper Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFHEA accreditation</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/afhea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:17:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/afhea/</guid>
      <description>My application was successful so I have been awarded Associate Fellowship of the HEA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoc applications</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/cv-end-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/cv-end-phd/</guid>
      <description>I have put together:
 Cover letter (source) Curriculum vitae (source) List of publications (this is included in the CV, but some applications ask for it separately) Research statement (source)  for applying for postdoctoral research associate/assistant/award (PDRA) positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</guid>
      <description>In our preprint appearing on arXiv today, Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC, we use the two-loop amplitudes from Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders along with the real corrections to obtain differential cross sections of gluon-initiated diphoton-plus-jet production at NLO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the preprint release, our paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance HE Associate Fellowship application</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:45:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</guid>
      <description>To improve my teaching in higher education, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a course at Durham called Gateway to Academic Practice. It leads to the Durham Excellence in Learning and Teaching Award Level 1 and Associate Fellowship of Advance HE. It is aligned to Descriptor 1 of the UK Professional Standards Framework (which explains the following [AKV]\d). Here&amp;rsquo;s my account of professional practice (source), which I&amp;rsquo;ll submit for assessment.
A2: Teaching and the Support of Learning This year I am a workshop demonstrator in level four Particle Theory for MPhys Theoretical Physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD completion review</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-completion-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 09:27:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-completion-report/</guid>
      <description>With nine months to go, I had to write up a completion review (source) for my PhD. This was a good opportunity to reflect on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and sketch out the shape of my thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</guid>
      <description>Our new paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was listed on the arXiv today. I posted about the code for this project yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>n3jet_diphoton version 1 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 15:47:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</guid>
      <description>Our project n3jet_diphoton demonstrates the use of neural networks for high precision scattering amplitudes within Monte Carlo event generator simulations for hadronic colliders. We finalised the code today along with a preprint submission that will be listed on the arXiv tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</guid>
      <description>Today the preprint of our article Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders appeared on arXiv, in which we compute the two-loop gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude, providing it ready for phenomenological application in an accompanying NJet release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NJet version 3 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</guid>
      <description>Today I released a new version of NJet. It includes all the feature contributions I have made to the NJet library over the last two years, including a couple of two-loop analytic amplitudes as well as some one-loop diphoton processes and a library of infrared limit functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YTF20: introduction to precision QCD</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</guid>
      <description>I was on the committee for the YTF 2019 and YTF 2020 conferences. For YTF20, I also gave a non-specialist talk on precision QCD. The talk is recorded (see below) and the slides are available here (source) (discussion of tech).
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV update</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</guid>
      <description>When applying to the SAGEX School in Mathematica and Maple, I had to provide a CV, which was good motivation to update my CV (source) and current research statement (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach with a Galton board</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</guid>
      <description>At the IPPP, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the outreach programme. Aside from helping to run events, I also did a bit of maintenance on the Galton board exhibit, which I wrote about on our Computing Club website. In recent quarantined times, I experimented with a virtual version (source), which I discussed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared factorisation properties of QCD amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</guid>
      <description>I typed up some notes (pdf) (source) about this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BUSSTEPP: precision QCD with diphotons</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</guid>
      <description>I attended the British Universities Summer School in Theoretical Elementary Particle Physics (BUSSTEPP) 2019. We all gave a short presentation of our research. Here are my slides (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD first year report: real QCD corrections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</guid>
      <description>The time has come for my first year progress assessment. Here&amp;rsquo;s my report (source).
This draws together my studies of:
 Modern techniques in calculating scattering amplitudes (notes) Spinor helicity formalism (source) Colour algebra for squared amplitudes (notes) QCD corrections to the cross section of electron-positron annihilation to hadrons (source) (notes)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous symmetries in dual-mode Dicke models</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/dicke-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/dicke-proj/</guid>
      <description>My final-year undergraduate research project, supervised by Jonathan Keeling and Kyle Ballantine, involved modelling non-equilibrium quantum systems to explore the continuous symmetries they can exhibit. Before starting original work, I conducted a literature review, summarised in my report (source). I then developed a Python simulation of the two-mode Dicke model to study its quantum phases. I wrote up the project in my dissertation (source). I also presented a poster (source) and defended the work in my viva with a presentation (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD applications</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m applying for PhDs just now. Have a look at my CV or statement of purpose if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarisation in photon Bose-Einstein condensation</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/bec-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/bec-proj/</guid>
      <description>My second summer research project was with Jonathan Keeling and Peter Kirton, modelling the polarisation behaviour of a Bose-Einstein condensate of photons. I wrote a Python code to simulate the system for this study. I reported (source) and presented a poster (source) on the work at the end of the summer.
In the next academic term, I gave a presentation (source) to fellow undergraduates in my department. I also continued work on the project, leading to a paper (arXiv).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laidlaw Scholarship Experiences</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/laidlaw-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/laidlaw-blog/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was featured on Laidlaw Scholarship Experiences. It concerns my project on photon BECs.
BEC Hello everyone, I hope you are all doing well.
(Do you get the joke of the title? It is condensed and I am studying condensates! No, OK, it is not very funny…)
I have thoroughly enjoyed reading through all the posts before mine. Thank you all for sharing your experiences and in such excellent prose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of the tight-binding model</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/solid-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/solid-state/</guid>
      <description>As part of the module PH3012 Thermal and Statistical Physics, we did a study of the one-dimensional tight-binding model of solid state physics. I wrote this report, with source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of a Brownian particle in an optical trap</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/compphys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/compphys/</guid>
      <description>The Mathematica source code is available here and the report here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I gained from the Professional Skills Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/psc/</guid>
      <description>This essay is also available as a pdf
I decided to enroll for the Professional Skills Curriculum (PSC) following advice from friends who had previously completed the course. They recommended it as a useful and informative experience in self-reflection and personal development. These are ideals I put effort into achieving, previously focussed by the Transferable Skills for Physicists module I took in Junior Honours. PSC provided me with a great opportunity to continue honing my professional skills with the guidance of its framework and access to its resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling electron states in silicon-based quantum computers</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/qc-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/qc-proj/</guid>
      <description>Over the summer of 2015, I worked on my first research project with Brendon Lovett and Giuseppe Pica. We investigated the quadrupole interaction between donor electrons in a silicon substrate by computational simulation with a view to guiding experiments in quantum computation. I produced a Python code to do this. I presented a poster (source) and wrote a report (source) on the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum computers and the cluster state</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/qc-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/qc-essay/</guid>
      <description>The module PH3014 Transferrable Skills for Physicists is a unique highlight of the St Andrews Physics Undergraduate programme. I had Paul Cruickshank as advisor for the module and enjoyed it greatly, developing my skills in oral and written communication and team work. In particular, I made good progress with my fear of public speaking.
The module includes a literature review project in which we produce a report on a topic and give a presentation on it at the wonderful Burn conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
