<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>terminal on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>//eidoom.github.io/tags/terminal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terminal on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:12:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//eidoom.github.io/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Neovim</title>
      <link>//eidoom.github.io/post/neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//eidoom.github.io/post/neovim/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been using vim as one of my go-to text editors for some time. I decided to replace it with Neovim, or nvim, and configure it from scratch using vim-bootstrap. vim-bootstrap uses vim-plug as the (n)vim package manager, which is what I was using previously with vim.
Installation I installed nvim and prerequisites for packages and vim-bootstrap
sudo dnf install ncurses-devel git ctags-etags curl neovim python3-neovim python3-pyflakes python3-jedi python3-flake8 vim-go ripgrep sudo npm install -g neovim  Change default I set nvim as the default terminal text editor and aliased calls to vi and vim</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring tmux</title>
      <link>//eidoom.github.io/post/tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 11:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//eidoom.github.io/post/tmux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To have multiple windows and panes in my terminal, I use the terminal multiplexer tmux. I installed it with
sudo dnf install tmux  Configuration The tmux configuration is stored at ~/.tmux.conf. I initially customised it as
$ vi ~/.tmux.conf  # Set zsh as default shell set -g default-shell /bin/zsh # Set indexing to match the keyboard set -g base-index 1 # Automatically set window title setw -g automatic-rename on set -g set-titles on # Mouse mode set -g mouse on # Alt-arrow without prefix key to switch panes bind -n M-Left select-pane -L bind -n M-Down select-pane -D bind -n M-Up select-pane -U bind -n M-Right select-pane -R # Shift-arrow without prefix key to switch windows bind -n S-Left previous-window bind -n S-Right next-window # Reload tmux config bind r source-file ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>