<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computing on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>//eidoom.github.io/categories/computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computing on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 12:41:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//eidoom.github.io/categories/computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home network ad-blocking with Pi-hole</title>
      <link>//eidoom.github.io/post/home-network-ad-blocking-with-pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//eidoom.github.io/post/home-network-ad-blocking-with-pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>Pi-hole is an awesome piece of software which blocks ads across a network at the name resolution level. Check out the source here. I set it up on my home linux server.
I hoped into my git repos folder and cloned the Pi-hole repo
cd ~/git git clone git@github.com:pi-hole/pi-hole.git  then used the installation scripts to install it on my system
cd ~/git/pi-hole/automated\ install sudo ./basic-install.sh  I chose CloudFlare as my Upstream DNS Provider because they have a good privacy policy and came out on top for performance in my ping tests</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing the Transmission web client by hostname</title>
      <link>//eidoom.github.io/post/address-transmission-web-client-using-hostname/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 09:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//eidoom.github.io/post/address-transmission-web-client-using-hostname/</guid>
      <description>I have Transmission running on my linux server for BitTorrent transfers. I have been accessing the web interface using the IP address of the server in the URL like a dirty animal. It&amp;rsquo;s time to use the hostname of my server for this.
Before making any changes to the settings, Transmission has to be stopped otherwise it will overwrite those changes.
sudo systemctl stop transmission-daemon  Open the settings for editing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonding ethernet interfaces on Debian Buster</title>
      <link>//eidoom.github.io/post/bonding-ethernet-interfaces-on-debian-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 16:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//eidoom.github.io/post/bonding-ethernet-interfaces-on-debian-stretch/</guid>
      <description>I set up my linux server to use its two ethernet interfaces in parallel. My primary reference was from the Debian wiki.
Migrating to systemd-networkd I used systemd-networkd to configure the bond interface. My system already uses systemd, so I just had to enable systemd-networkd.
sudo systemctl enable systemd-networkd  I also set up systemd-resolved to provide name resolution.
sudo systemctl enable systemd-resolved ln -sf /run/systemd/resolve/stub-resolv.conf /etc/resolv.conf  Over the years, I have used various networking solutions on this machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>