<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>professional development on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/categories/professional-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in professional development on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:45:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/categories/professional-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advance HE Associate Fellowship application</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:45:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</guid>
      <description>To improve my teaching in higher education, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a course at Durham called Gateway to Academic Practice. It leads to the Durham Excellence in Learning and Teaching Award Level 1 and Associate Fellowship of Advance HE. It is aligned to Descriptor 1 of the UK Professional Standards Framework (which explains the following [AKV]\d). Here&amp;rsquo;s my account of professional practice (source), which I&amp;rsquo;ll submit for assessment.
A2: Teaching and the Support of Learning This year I am a workshop demonstrator in level four Particle Theory for MPhys Theoretical Physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laidlaw Scholarship Experiences</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/laidlaw-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/laidlaw-blog/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was featured on Laidlaw Scholarship Experiences. It concerns my project on photon BECs.
BEC Hello everyone, I hope you are all doing well.
(Do you get the joke of the title? It is condensed and I am studying condensates! No, OK, it is not very funny…)
I have thoroughly enjoyed reading through all the posts before mine. Thank you all for sharing your experiences and in such excellent prose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I gained from the Professional Skills Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/psc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/psc/</guid>
      <description>This essay is also available as a pdf
I decided to enroll for the Professional Skills Curriculum (PSC) following advice from friends who had previously completed the course. They recommended it as a useful and informative experience in self-reflection and personal development. These are ideals I put effort into achieving, previously focussed by the Transferable Skills for Physicists module I took in Junior Honours. PSC provided me with a great opportunity to continue honing my professional skills with the guidance of its framework and access to its resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
