<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>amplitudes on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/tags/amplitudes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in amplitudes on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/tags/amplitudes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: optimising hadronic collider simulations using amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat-proc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat-proc/</guid>
      <description>The preprint for my ACAT2021 proceedings contribution, Optimising hadronic collider simulations using amplitude neural networks, appeared on arXiv today. This follows my recent talk. It is also available through the GitLab CI system here (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phys. Let. B: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, the open access version of our paper Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC was published online in Physics Letters B today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACAT 2021 talk: optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat/</guid>
      <description>I gave a virtual talk at ACAT2021 (while I had COVID, actually) about our recent paper. Here are the slides (source) and a recording (below). Apologies for where the audio cuts out in the middle, but it&amp;rsquo;s really Zoom&amp;rsquo;s fault for not supporting Linux well.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, our paper Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</guid>
      <description>In our preprint appearing on arXiv today, Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC, we use the two-loop amplitudes from Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders along with the real corrections to obtain differential cross sections of gluon-initiated diphoton-plus-jet production at NLO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the preprint release, our paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</guid>
      <description>Our new paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was listed on the arXiv today. I posted about the code for this project yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</guid>
      <description>Today the preprint of our article Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders appeared on arXiv, in which we compute the two-loop gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude, providing it ready for phenomenological application in an accompanying NJet release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared factorisation properties of QCD amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</guid>
      <description>I typed up some notes (pdf) (source) about this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BUSSTEPP: precision QCD with diphotons</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</guid>
      <description>I attended the British Universities Summer School in Theoretical Elementary Particle Physics (BUSSTEPP) 2019. We all gave a short presentation of our research. Here are my slides (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD first year report: real QCD corrections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</guid>
      <description>The time has come for my first year progress assessment. Here&amp;rsquo;s my report (source).
This draws together my studies of:
 Modern techniques in calculating scattering amplitudes (notes) Spinor helicity formalism (source) Colour algebra for squared amplitudes (notes) QCD corrections to the cross section of electron-positron annihilation to hadrons (source) (notes)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
