<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>phd on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/tags/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in phd on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 12:55:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PhD Thesis</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 12:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/thesis/</guid>
      <description>I am writing my PhD thesis (source) now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: optimising hadronic collider simulations using amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat-proc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat-proc/</guid>
      <description>The preprint for my ACAT2021 proceedings contribution, Optimising hadronic collider simulations using amplitude neural networks, appeared on arXiv today. This follows my recent talk. It is also available through the GitLab CI system here (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cavendish HEP seminar: NLO QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/cavendish-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/cavendish-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk in the Cavendish HEP seminar series. It covered the same content as a previous talk. Here are the slides (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPPP internal seminar: NLO QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at hadron colliders</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ippp-internal-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ippp-internal-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk in the IPPP internal seminar series about my recent work on diphoton-plus-jet production via gluon fusion, including:
 Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks  Here are the slides (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phys. Let. B: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 18:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-xs-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, the open access version of our paper Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC was published online in Physics Letters B today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACAT 2021 talk: optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/acat/</guid>
      <description>I gave a virtual talk at ACAT2021 (while I had COVID, actually) about our recent paper. Here are the slides (source) and a recording (below). Apologies for where the audio cuts out in the middle, but it&amp;rsquo;s really Zoom&amp;rsquo;s fault for not supporting Linux well.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ggyyg-amp/</guid>
      <description>Following the arXiv release, our paper Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFHEA accreditation</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/afhea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:17:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/afhea/</guid>
      <description>My application was successful so I have been awarded Associate Fellowship of the HEA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: NLO gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet cross sections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-xs-pp/</guid>
      <description>In our preprint appearing on arXiv today, Next-to-leading order QCD corrections to diphoton-plus-jet production through gluon fusion at the LHC, we use the two-loop amplitudes from Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders along with the real corrections to obtain differential cross sections of gluon-initiated diphoton-plus-jet production at NLO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JHEP: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pub/</guid>
      <description>Following the preprint release, our paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was published by the Journal of High Energy Physics today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance HE Associate Fellowship application</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:45:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/delta1/</guid>
      <description>To improve my teaching in higher education, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a course at Durham called Gateway to Academic Practice. It leads to the Durham Excellence in Learning and Teaching Award Level 1 and Associate Fellowship of Advance HE. It is aligned to Descriptor 1 of the UK Professional Standards Framework (which explains the following [AKV]\d). Here&amp;rsquo;s my account of professional practice (source), which I&amp;rsquo;ll submit for assessment.
A2: Teaching and the Support of Learning This year I am a workshop demonstrator in level four Particle Theory for MPhys Theoretical Physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD completion review</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-completion-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 09:27:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-completion-report/</guid>
      <description>With nine months to go, I had to write up a completion review (source) for my PhD. This was a good opportunity to reflect on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and sketch out the shape of my thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</guid>
      <description>Our new paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was listed on the arXiv today. I posted about the code for this project yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>n3jet_diphoton version 1 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 15:47:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</guid>
      <description>Our project n3jet_diphoton demonstrates the use of neural networks for high precision scattering amplitudes within Monte Carlo event generator simulations for hadronic colliders. We finalised the code today along with a preprint submission that will be listed on the arXiv tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arXiv: gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</guid>
      <description>Today the preprint of our article Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders appeared on arXiv, in which we compute the two-loop gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet amplitude, providing it ready for phenomenological application in an accompanying NJet release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NJet version 3 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</guid>
      <description>Today I released a new version of NJet. It includes all the feature contributions I have made to the NJet library over the last two years, including a couple of two-loop analytic amplitudes as well as some one-loop diphoton processes and a library of infrared limit functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YTF20: introduction to precision QCD</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</guid>
      <description>I was on the committee for the YTF 2019 and YTF 2020 conferences. For YTF20, I also gave a non-specialist talk on precision QCD. The talk is recorded (see below) and the slides are available here (source) (discussion of tech).
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV update</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</guid>
      <description>When applying to the SAGEX School in Mathematica and Maple, I had to provide a CV, which was good motivation to update my CV (source) and current research statement (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach with a Galton board</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</guid>
      <description>At the IPPP, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the outreach programme. Aside from helping to run events, I also did a bit of maintenance on the Galton board exhibit, which I wrote about on our Computing Club website. In recent quarantined times, I experimented with a virtual version (source), which I discussed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared factorisation properties of QCD amplitudes</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ir/</guid>
      <description>I typed up some notes (pdf) (source) about this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BUSSTEPP: precision QCD with diphotons</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</guid>
      <description>I attended the British Universities Summer School in Theoretical Elementary Particle Physics (BUSSTEPP) 2019. We all gave a short presentation of our research. Here are my slides (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD first year report: real QCD corrections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</guid>
      <description>The time has come for my first year progress assessment. Here&amp;rsquo;s my report (source).
This draws together my studies of:
 Modern techniques in calculating scattering amplitudes (notes) Spinor helicity formalism (source) Colour algebra for squared amplitudes (notes) QCD corrections to the cross section of electron-positron annihilation to hadrons (source) (notes)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD applications</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m applying for PhDs just now. Have a look at my CV or statement of purpose if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
