<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>phd on Ryan Moodie</title>
    <link>https://eidoom.github.io/tags/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in phd on Ryan Moodie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eidoom.github.io/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gluon fusion to diphoton plus jets with amplitude neural networks</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-pp/</guid>
      <description>Our new paper Optimising simulations for diphoton production at hadron colliders using amplitude neural networks was listed on the arXiv today. I posted about the code for this project yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>n3jet_diphoton version 1 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 15:47:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/nn-repo/</guid>
      <description>Our project n3jet_diphoton demonstrates the use of neural networks for high precision scattering amplitudes within Monte Carlo event generator simulations for hadronic colliders. We finalised the code today along with a preprint submission that will be listed on the arXiv tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluon fusion to diphoton plus jet at two loops</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/3g2a-2l/</guid>
      <description>Today the preprint of our article Virtual QCD corrections to gluon-initiated diphoton plus jet production at hadron colliders appeared on the arXiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NJet version 3 release</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/njet3/</guid>
      <description>Today I released a new version of NJet. It includes all the feature contributions I have made to the NJet library over the last two years, including a couple of two-loop analytic amplitudes as well as some one-loop diphoton processes and a library of infrared limit functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YTF20 presentation: introduction to precision QCD</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/ytf20/</guid>
      <description>I was on the committee for the YTF 2019 and YTF 2020 conferences. For YTF20, I also gave a non-specialist talk on precision QCD. The talk is recorded and the slides are available here (source) (discussion of tech).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV update</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/statement/</guid>
      <description>When applying to the SAGEX School in Mathematica and Maple, I had to provide a CV, which was good motivation to update my CV (source) and current research statement (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach with a Galton board</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/outreach/</guid>
      <description>At the IPPP, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the outreach programme. Aside from helping to run events, I also did a bit of maintenance on the Galton board exhibit, which I wrote about on our Computing Club website. In recent quarantined times, I experimented with a virtual version (source), which I discussed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BUSSTEPP presentation: precision QCD with diphotons</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/busstepp/</guid>
      <description>I attended British Universities Summer School in Theoretical Elementary Particle Physics 2019. We all gave a short presentation of our research. Here are my slides (alt) (source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD first year report: real QCD corrections</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-year-one-report/</guid>
      <description>The time has come for my first year progress assessment. Here&amp;rsquo;s my report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD applications</title>
      <link>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eidoom.github.io/post/phd-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m applying for PhDs just now. Have a look at my CV or statement of purpose if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
